<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on Vidyasagar Bhargava</title>
    <link>/categories/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on Vidyasagar Bhargava</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Python for Data Science 🐍</title>
      <link>/2019/07/python-for-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/07/python-for-data-science/</guid>
      <description>Help and Documentation in PythonNumpyPandasMatplotlibScikit-learnHelp and Documentation in python:Every python object contains the reference to a string, known as doc string, which contain a concise summary of the object and how to use it. Python has built-in help() function that can access this information and prints the result.
For example to see the documentation of built-in function len() :-
help(len)## Help on built-in function len in module builtins:## ## len(obj, /)## Return the number of items in a container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Python Crash Course - Part 2</title>
      <link>/2019/07/basic-python-crash-course-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/07/basic-python-crash-course-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Python is an “Object Oriented Programming language” or OOP for short. It is a programming paradigm which focuses on reusable pattern of code, in contrast to procedural programming, which focuses on explicit sequenced instructions. When working on complex programs, object oriented programming let you reuse code and write code that is more readable, which in turn makes it more maintainable.
Table of contentsClasses and objectsAttributes and methods in classInstance attributeClass attributeObject inheritanceParent Vs Child class 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic python crash course - Part 1</title>
      <link>/2019/07/basic-python-crash-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/07/basic-python-crash-course/</guid>
      <description>Python is most popular programming language among data scientists across the world and like high level languages, python is easy to read, take less time to write and is portable. So in this post we will learn about basics of python which includes variables, numbers conditionals, functions, list, dictionary, set, expression etc…
Table of Contents:-Variable, Numbers and Strings
Conditionals
Functions
List, dictionary, Set, Expression 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning in Python</title>
      <link>/2019/06/machine-learning-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/machine-learning-in-python/</guid>
      <description>In this post we will see demo of two machine learning problems using python. We will train model on two different datasets using two different type of machine learning algorithm one for classifier and other for regression.The learning algorithm finds the pattern in the training data which maps the input data features to target variable and it outputs an machine learning model that captures these patterns. Also we will learn about scikit-learn library in detail (coming soon).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>