<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Vidyasagar Bhargava</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Vidyasagar Bhargava</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gradient Descent from scratch and visualization</title>
      <link>/2019/06/gradient-descent-from-scratch-and-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/gradient-descent-from-scratch-and-visualization/</guid>
      <description>Gradient descent is an optimization algorithm used to find the values of parameters (coefficients) of a function (f) that minimizes a cost function. There are alot of blogs and videos on youtube about this topic. So therefore we are not going into theory here.
In this video from coursera machine learning course Andrew NG discusses about gradient descent algorithm. Its good have spend some time on this video and get intuition about it before we start writing code for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Pipeline in Python</title>
      <link>/2019/06/machine-learning-pipeline-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/machine-learning-pipeline-in-python/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post we will see introduction to machine learning using python. We will code two different type of machinelearning pipe line one for classifier and other for regression on toy datasets. These both pipelines can be used as a template for machine learning problem. A part from that we will learn about scikit-learn library. In the coming post we will use pipeline on more complex dataset from kaggle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Softmax function from scratch</title>
      <link>/2019/06/softmax-function-from-scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/softmax-function-from-scratch/</guid>
      <description>Softmax is a generalization of logistic regression which can be use for multi-class classification. The softmax function squashes the outputs of each unit to be between 0 and 1, just like a sigmoid function. But it also divides each output such that the total sum of the outputs is equal to 1.
Softmax Function :-
Softmax is a generalization of logistic regression which can be use for multi-class classification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidyverse Style titanic kaggle competition</title>
      <link>/2019/06/tidyverse-style-titanic-kaggle-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/06/tidyverse-style-titanic-kaggle-competition/</guid>
      <description>This post is an effort of showing a new approach of modelling in R using tidyverse and tidymodels.We will go through step by step from data import to final model evaluation process in machine learning. We will not just focus on coding part but also the statistical aspect should be taken into account behind the modelling process. In this tutorial we are using titanic dataset from Kaggle competition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animation in R</title>
      <link>/2019/05/animation-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/animation-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays many data scientist are beginning to think about how to make their visualization more compelling with animation. Animation might help a viewer work through the logic behind anidea by showing the intermediate steps and transitions, or show how data collected over time changes. A moving image might offer a fresh perspective, or invite users to look deeper into the data presented. An animation might also smooth the change between two views, even if there is no temporal component to the data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>